Stay together, let's go!
Blow through the window.
Uh oh, here comes trouble.
You could've killed him.
Yeah, you need a lawyer?
Hey, never ever
let go of that hose.
It's your lifeline, the way out.
You're lucky
I don't need a coroner.
I'm sorry, [mumbles].
You shouldn't be
on your leg, man.
Nah, I'll be fine.
Don't ask me to stop
doin' what I love.
All I've ever wanted to
do was drive that truck.
My pops, his pops, and now me.
Okay?
Okay.
I don't know about
your friend here.
You really oughta do
somethin' about that asthma.
Don't try and
change the subject.
I'm just thinkin' maybe
I'm not cut out for this.
I thought you
loved bein' a fireman.
I do.
The rush, the excitement,
it's got its perks.
Then what's the problem?
Yeah, see?
People don't think
about the ugly side.
They just fall in love with
the uniform, but it's not easy.
You just gotta find a
place in your mind to put it.
Yeah, some of
the things we see
trust me you don't
wanna remember.
I just feel like
somethin's missin'.
Well, you better decide
'cause this is your life.
Yeah, try tellin'
that to Spoon.
Two days in the air
finally caught up with me.
Yeah, I could tell.
Another horoscope?
"Take a look in the
mirror, let go of the past
"and focus on the here and now.
"Your life depends on it."
That's common sense.
That's your horoscope.
The problem is you don't listen.
Waste of paper and good ink.
It's the stars that
make the world go 'round.
What?
Are you ever gonna paint again?
Are you ever gonna
finish that book
you've been writin'
for damn near a decade?
Seven years and yes.
They say poetry doesn't sell.
The Arms Association
is having an art show.
I think you should
enter somethin'.
Yeah, I lost to my passion.
Well it's my job to
help you get it back.
- Hey, hey!
- Hey.
Ah, this guy.
the perfect life.
Yup, five years strong.
Happy anniversary.
Ooh, thank you!
Yeah, man.
It just keeps playin'
over and over in my mind.
Sometimes it's hard to shake.
I've been doing this
a lot longer than you.
It comes with the territory.
Trust me.
You're gonna see a lot of things
you wish you could forget.
I coulda got a lifetime
without seein' that
old guy like that.
Old guy was homeless, man.
Somebody loved him.
Don't matter now.
Nope.
Listenin' to his tales about
when he worked on Wall
Street, did you believe him?
Yeah, I did.
Did you?
Hell naw.
Well he's gone now.
Just like that.
You know that's my biggest fear.
Bein' homeless?
Dyin' alone.
So you love him,
or is it the fact
that he'll be Marlon Jones MD
that keeps you waiting for
a man that's miles away?
I love him.
Has he asked you
to marry him yet?
Do you see a ring?
What about Caleb?
Girl, he's got Breanna.
She is successful.
She's bright,
except when it comes to him.
Yeah, I don't know why she
puts up with him exactly.
Uh--
Okay, maybe I do.
I could only
think of one reason.
She loves his crusty underuse.
He just hasn't found
the right one yet.
He hasn't found the right
one because he's not looking.
Mmm, mmm, mmm, my baby
sure can cook can't she?
Jack of all trades.
How did I get so lucky?
The uniform.
Guess who I ran
into at the gym?
Asia
Redmon?
Yeah, I guess she's
not Redmon anymore.
I guess.
Didn't she marry
that pilot?
So that's funny to you?
I'm just givin' information.
Alright, aight.
Whoa!
I'm okay.
He just had to bring that up.
I'm disappointed
in you Caleb Abrams.
He had it comin', ma.
Maybe he did, but still.
Baby, when are you
gonna let this go?
I just can't see myself
lovin' somebody all new.
I know what it's
like to be in love
and it's not supposed
to feel like that.
Can't believe
it's been a year.
Apologize to Bryce.
He brought it on hisself.
Apologize anyway.
You guys have been
friends since childhood.
So?
So part of bein' a man is
acceptin' responsibilities
and that includes
saying you're sorry.
You're startin'
to sound like Spoon.
You need to call your dad.
I don't feel like
hearing his mouth.
Hey, that's still your daddy.
Now let's eat some of
this cake while it's hot.
Haven't seen you in
church in a month of Sundays.
Not that long.
You too busy for the Lord?
No Spoon, you know
better than that.
Is this painting gonna
get you into Heaven?
Probably not.
Neither is fighting fires.
Time I was your
age, I had you.
I was married.
What you tryin' to say, Spoon?
It's time to grow up.
This is my life.
Get out of here!
When I tell you to get out
of there, that's what I mean!
You split up the team!
You put us all in jeopardy!
If this had been a real
fire, you'd be dead!
Strike two!
What are you doin' here?
What now?
I wanted to surprise you.
What, did you
think it was Imani?
Come on, that's my roommate.
Plus she got her own
bed and her own room.
- Yeah, she better.
- You did surprise me though.
- I did?
- Yeah, you did.
I did surprise you
'cause I missed you.
Did you miss me?
I missed you, boy.
Show me how much
you missed me.
So, lemme hear it.
Hear what?
Not a word from you in
days, what's your excuse?
I didn't know I needed one.
One day I'm gonna break
up with you for good.
I thought you loved me.
I do sometimes.
That's not what you
were sayin' a minute ago.
Is that all this is?
What more do you
want from me, girl?
I can't keep doin'
this wit you, Caleb.
Do you love me?
I just showed you.
You know what I think?
I think you waitin'
for her to come back.
Tell me I'm wrong.
You shouldn't have let her in.
I think you should
give her a chance.
A chance for what?
I don't know, to grow on you.
Like fungus?
I don't know
but at some point,
you're gonna have to
let your guard down.
As much as your
head is in that book,
you should know everything
there is to know about history.
That's the plan.
I can't believe I'm
about to be a dad.
What if I'm not good at it?
What if you are?
You're gonna be a great dad.
- I'm a good husband.
- Yes, you are.
Still, I'm a little scared.
You run into burnin'
buildings for a living.
This is different.
Yeah, well either way it goes,
you're responsible
for a human life.
I don't feel like
that goin' into a fire.
Can't afford to be scared.
I might not make it out.
Suppose he doesn't
ask you to marry him.
Then I guess I'm
stuck with you.
Wow, is that such a bad thing?
I pay my half of
the bills at least.
That's more than most.
Look, just don't
bet the farm on it.
Why would you say that?
Because you should be spendin'
this time writin' your book
instead of wastin'
your time on this.
Well who asked you?
I'm just sayin'.
Thank God I'm gonna
be gone a few days.
That means I get
the house to myself?
Yeah.
Ooh.
Asia.
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
What are you doin' here?
I came to say I'm sorry.
A year later?
You weren't ready, Caleb.
I wasn't ready?
You tried to
find your passion.
I needed stability.
And you didn't believe in me.
I made a mistake.
I made a mistake when
I opened that door.
No table talking.
- Shh.
Excuse me, we have
an announcement.
Bam.
Hold up, hold up, hold up.
Got a prenup?
- Really?
- What?
- Are you serious?
- Seriously?
Half of all marriages
end in divorce.
Yes?
- But half of 'em don't.
- But half of 'em do.
- a man see.
- Congratulations.
- I'm just sayin',
I'm just sayin'.
- Cheers.
- Yes, yes.
Cheers.
- Wedding dress shopping.
- Yeah!
Hey, I thought you
were gonna wait for me.
I didn't think you'd
be in any condition
to run this mornin'.
That sleep foam
mattress, I tell you.
Yeah, I tell you.
It's the best.
I need to get me one.
So what do you think?
I'm so proud of you.
It's not done yet but--
It's time you got
back in the game.
I have to admit,
sometimes I wonder.
Who's gonna believe in you
if you don't believe in you?
Yeah, but when your own
pops don't believe in you?
Then you're just
gonna have to show him.
This
is my passion.
It's not some hobby.
Some people spend their
entire lives searchin' for that.
Consider yourself blessed.
Shelby [chuckles], my brother.
Yes.
Caleb.
So
I hear that you're
painting again.
- Yup.
- Yeah.
Sell one.
Just one painting
and I promise you'll never
have to hear it from me again.
I don't have to prove anything
to anybody including you.
Yeah, you do.
Yeah, prove that that
art degree of yours
is worth more than the
paper it's printed on.
That's all I'm sayin'.
Don't get your Ivy
League ass whooped.
And about that?
Touch me again and I promise
I'll have you standin'
in front of a judge.
I think he knows that.
A penny for your thoughts?
I'm thinkin' I'd
like to make love to you again.
Just gimme like five minutes.
Wanna know what I'm thinking?
I'm thinking I want a family,
a baby,
the minivan, the dog,
I want the whole nine.
I'm thinkin' you
need to slow down.
Well I wasn't
raised like this.
Like I want to get
married, Caleb.
Is that a crime?
It is if you're
tryin' to marry to me.
Don't I deserve that?
Yeah.
You do deserve that.
You're career-oriented, CPA.
You're independent.
What man wouldn't
want a woman like you?
Then what is the
problem, Caleb?
I just don't think I
can give you all of that,
to be honest.
I'm the closest thing you
have to a girlfriend, right?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, I just I can't help
that I want you all to myself.
I love you.
I've been thinkin'.
Uh oh.
What do you think?
What is it?
Can't you tell?
Babe, it's an ashtray.
Oh, okay but we
don't smoke though.
After the baby turns a year,
I might try my hand at
starting up a new business.
Baby, you don't
need to do that.
Why not?
Don't I take good care of you?
Yes, you're a great
provider but still.
But still what?
I have goals, too.
But baby, you have us.
It doesn't end there, Shelby.
I need you here.
You get to live
your dream every day.
What about me?
Man, a woman is supposed
to be in the house.
My wife is gonna be at home.
What planet are you from, man?
My mom was always at home.
Yeah you didn't marry your
mom, you married Jasmyn.
If she wants to start
her own business,
you probably should support her.
We've been through
this a million times.
She's always comin'
up with these ideas.
Don't matter, she's
always supported you.
Whose side are you on?
Come on man, that
ain't gonna work
in today's day and age.
I know but you
should've seen it,
I didn't even know what it was.
She said it was an
ashtray or somethin'.
At the
end of the day,
she loves you from
the crown of your head
to the bottom of
yo stinky soles.
How do you know?
It's obvious.
I guess she caught herself
bein' on strike or somethin'.
Ooh, so now we get
to the real problem.
I gotta sneak up on her
in the middle of the night.
It's killin' me, man.
Aww, you need a hug?
Yeah, that's not all I need.
Not from me.
No, thank you.
- Hey, what's up?
- Hey.
Shelby's not off
'til seven, right?
Right, yeah.
Are you staying for dinner?
Don't gimme that look.
I thought we agreed that we
wouldn't bring that up again.
Yeah, but it's killin' me.
Trust me.
If I could take
it back, I would.
It's not like I
set out to do it.
Can't we just
put that behind us
and act like it didn't happen?
Look, I didn't come
here to upset you okay?
Are you sure it's his?
I'm sure.
And if it's not?
It is.
He better never find out.
Then you better
take it to the grave.
It's just a little rain.
How can you sleep
through all of that?
Easy.
Sorry for barging
in like this.
It's alright, stay
as long as you need to.
You can't go
back to sleep yet.
Yeah, who gonna stop me?
Please just stay up with
me 'til the storm's over?
Okay, okay, okay.
I have somethin' to
talk to you about anyway.
Can I ask you a question?
But I need you to be
100% honest with me.
What is it?
I've come up with a title.
- For your book?
- Mm-hmm.
Well tell me, what is it?
Naked Poetics.
Naked Poetics?
Naked as in candid,
what do you think?
I love it.
Yeah, for real.
Now finish writin'
the damn book.
Goodnight.
Ooh, game point.
That [mumbles], I wouldn't
marry yo ass either.
Look I just
finished my residency
and Imani know anythin'
about the ring.
What it's about then?
About that four-letter
word, obviously.
Or more like that
three-letter word.
What's that supposed to mean?
Game.
Walls is pretty thin.
Man, I ain't have
nothin' to prove to you.
Aight, aight, aight, come on.
Hey, did I miss somethin'?
Yeah, the chip
on your boy's shoulder.
Whassup wit you, bro?
Sometimes I just don't get you.
Every time we do this, it's
like playin' Russian Roulette.
How when he's always away?
I'm not about to
be your boy toy.
Is that what you think?
Well what else am
I supposed to think?
Obviously this ain't love.
It is what it is.
And what's that
supposed to mean, Asia?
Since when have you
had a conscience, hmm?
Are you okay?
I feel like
somethin's not right.
Is that what your
horoscope says?
I know you and somethin's off.
I'm a big boy.
You can tell me.
You wouldn't understand.
Are you seein' her again?
Caleb, why?
I thought we didn't
have secrets.
I guess now we don't.
If you don't wanna
be with Breanna,
I think you need
to let her know.
I need you to mind
your own business.
Don't you got a wedding
to plan or somethin'?
You are playin'
a dangerous game.
Every day of my
life is dangerous.
Just a little
added protection.
This way if somethin'
happens to you, God forbid,
everything's all taken care of.
No worries.
This takes care of everything.
So now I can rest easy.
Knockin' on 40, bro.
It's time.
Hey, I appreciate you.
I know I don't show it
all the time but I do.
Come on man,
get outta the way.
Hi.
- Hi.
Hi, I have 'til
five o'clock right?
It's 5:01.
Come on, I have to
enter this competition.
That's not my problem,
come back tomorrow.
Tomorrow's too late.
We open at 9:00.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
I don't want you to,
but I understand
if you wanna go.
You have a choice, Caleb.
It's not you.
I just can't commit
to anybody right now.
You can't or you won't?
I'm at a crossroad.
Then maybe it's time
I explore my options.
Maybe.
You're not committed to me.
Right.
Which is all the more reason why
I can't keep
myself through this.
I just need to do some
soul searching, that's all.
Well, search all you want
but I can't promise
that I'll be here
when you figure it all out.
I am woman.
Despite your twisted and
sadistic views, I am woman.
Minus the thin thighs and
flowing hair, I am woman.
Proud of my rich skin tone,
coarse hair and full lips.
I am a woman with
a story to tell
and a past as deep
and dark as my roots.
I am a woman despite what
you think when you look down
your narrow nose upon me.
I am a woman enriched
with passion,
motivation and determination.
I possess dreams,
aspirations and knowledge.
So think twice with your
shallow minds and narrow vision.
For you may never know
what truly encompasses
the black woman.
Yeah.
Go!
Abrams!
Winter!
They should have
been out here by now.
Lord, we thank you
for [mumbles] today.
We thank you for
sun today, Lord.
I thank you for my wife.
Lord, we thank you for
the little blessings
that we tend to forget.
Oh Lord, I thank you for my son.
God and beyond his
wayward desires.
And Lord, we pray
for peace and harmony
around the table today, Lord.
And Lord, let
bygones be bygones.
In Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Amen!
So what brings you back?
Not now, Ruthie.
Then when?
The grass ain't as green
on the other side is it?
You could have said something
before those
invitations went out.
Mom, dad.
Boy, do I need to remind you?
I'm a grown man.
Yeah but there was no way this
could have ended well.
No way.
These yams are really
good, Miss Ruthie.
You did your thang.
Look girl, you
ain't big as a minute.
When you gonna have that baby?
Not soon enough.
Well at this rate I may
never have any grandchildren.
You never know Miss Ruthie.
You never know.
I'm having a boy you know.
Yeah, I can't wait.
Want you to be the godfather.
Hell yeah.
Goddamn.
Here come trouble.
Man whatever you did, I
think she's done this time.
It's what I didn't do.
What could you
possibly tell me
about Imani I
don't already know?
Everybody has skeletons.
Everybody.
So you better listen up.
Okay but there's
nothing he can say
that's gonna stop me from
wanting to marry her.
Alright.
What's the scheme?
Imani?
Imani is a good girl.
Come on man, seriously?
Her work shoes
stink but still,
she's a good girl.
So I'll buy some odor eaters.
A little on the
chunky side too.
I can live with that.
Nobody's perfect.
Not even my little Jasmyn.
That's what I'm
talkin' about bro.
I'll kill you if
you ever mistreat her.
Hmm?
Ohh now that
sounds like a threat.
Oh no, you can take
that to the bank.
Cash it.
Better watch it, dog.
You be alright.
we'll be back shortly.
I can't believe I
let you talk me into this.
I don't even like weddings.
Just this one time for me.
Alright, but you know
how i feel about it.
It would mean the world to me.
Your best man.
Isn't that a little weird?
No, this is my wedding.
We're doing it my way.
Alright.
I'll be in your little wedding.
Intimate, not little.
Whoa yeah baby!
Come on, seriously?
That's what I'm talking about.
You have to pay me.
- I ain't paying you.
- You have to pay me.
- No.
You must be Caleb.
Who wants to know?
I'm here so apparently I do.
You should have expected me.
Oh really?
Really.
Well you're here.
So you already have your answer.
So it's true.
I'm asking.
No wonder.
What am I supposed to do?
I can't leave him
here like this.
I didn't say the
wedding was off.
I don't know when.
Remember what the Lord said
to Moses about you and me
when we had Kadesh Barnea.
Caleb asked Joshua.
And I brought him back a report
according to my convictions.
But my brothers,
who went up with me,
made the hearts of the
people melt with fear.
I have defiled the Lord,
my God wholeheartedly.
You think I pulled
that name out of a hat?
I would hope you
put more thought
than that into it, dad.
It takes courage
to follow your heart.
Son, if you wanna paint, paint.
Lucky for you it went in
through your shoulder.
Lucky for me you're
not cashing in a policy.
You need to eat something.
It is not your job
to take care of me.
I know it's not.
You put your whole
life on hold for me.
What's your fiance gonna
think about all that?
I thought it'd be a good
idea to give Imani a break.
You've been running
that poor girl ragged.
Now don't you go feeling
sorry for yourself.
I knew one day it
would come back on me.
I just thought somehow it
would be tied to a fire.
Mom, I feel like a fool.
Baby, we've all been
there a time or two.
The best part of
this whole thing
is that you learn from it.
Well I have to go.
Don't look at me like that.
Caleb, I have to
get back to my life.
I understand.
Go.
Leave
a message at the tone.
Hey.
Thanks for the card.
I wanted to say something
that I didn't have
the heart to say
a long time ago.
I should have just
leveled with you
I'm sorry, Breanna.
I never meant to hurt you.
There is no excuse
for what we did.
If you blame anybody, blame me.
Oh oh, the dead has arisen.
- Ahhh.
- I'm sorry.
Poor choice of words.
Yeah, wrong shoulder too.
My bad, my bad.
What took you so long
to get over here?
Everybody's been
asking about you.
They wanna know when
you're coming back.
I don't know if or
when I'm coming back.
Thinking about taking on
this art thing full time.
Well if you change your mind,
we'll be happy to have you back.
You know, I was thinking too.
Not sure that I want my
boy to be a firefighter.
I mean he'll be
fourth generation.
I just want him to go
to school, you know.
Come out an engineer,
a doctor or something.
This is all I know.
You gotta see Jasmyn.
She's about ready to pop boy.
- Yeah?
- Yeah man.
Come on, let me get
you something to drink.
Hello.
Are you sure?
First place?
Yes, thank you!
First place.
- Yeah.
Hey don't forget about
us after you blow up.
That'll be long
after he's dead.
Guess that art degree is
worth somethin'.
Or pursuin' your passion.
- Cheers.
- Here, here.
If you don't wanna do this,
we can walk out
that door right now.
I just realized that I'm
losing my best friend today.
But you're gainin' a husband.
Then why aren't you dressed?
If you're not 100% sure
about a life-changing decision,
you have time to reconsider.
Havin' second thoughts?
Relax, man.
I just finished my residency.
Ey, ey, at least you
got a great lawyer.
What's the hold up?
You know my timing
couldn't be any worse.
Just say it.
I was gonna leave
it alone, but I'm not.
I love you, Imani.
I can cut you a
deal on my retainer.
Retainer, retainer?
Man, what's the hold up?
Ah ah, I would
advise you not to.
Would you stop bein'
lawyer for one damn minute?
What's goin' on?
How much time we got?
All is fair in
love and war, right?
You crossed the line.
This changes everything.
I'm gonna find out for myself.
No no no no no.
C'mon, whoa whoa
whoa, ey.
Okay, okay.
Okay someone please
tell me what's goin' on.
Yeah, tell us.
♪ The thick and thin
♪ When the fire
♪ Freezes me
♪ You'll be there
I'm in love with
my best friend.
♪ To Take my fear
♪ And wash it all away